Guide to the British Labour local authority archives,1983-1987.
British Labour local authority archives
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
British Labour local authority archives, 1983-1987.
6799
Peter B., Meyer 1943-
12 cubic ft.
Newspapers, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes documentation of his work for The Centre for Local Economic Strategies, a non-profit membership organization of Labour local governments; writing for the Local Economic Development Information System of The Planning Exchange, based in Glasgow; and government and non-profit agency documents describing local and regional economic development efforts.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Peter Meyer is professor emeritus of Urban Policy and Economics at the University of Louisville. In the 1980s, he did research in Britain on comparing local economic development strategies in Leeds, Cardiff, and Glasgow. The Centre for
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes documentation of his work for The Centre for Local Economic Strategies, a non-profit membership organization of Labour local governments; writing for the Local Economic Development Information System of The Planning Exchange, based in Glasgow; and government and non-profit agency documents describing local and regional economic development efforts.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Meyer, Peter B.,1943-
Subjects:
City planning--Great Britain.; Urban policy--Great Britain.; Economic development--Great Britain.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Wales, 1981-87 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Welsh Development Agency: Wales, 1981-87 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Welsh Development Agency: Land authority for Wales, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Welsh Development Agency: Trade Union Council report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Welsh Development Agency: Wales - industrial development initiatives in England and Wales: the role of the district councils, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Welsh Development Agency: Reports, 1983-91 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
- Welsh Development Agency: Wintech, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Wales, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sheffield: Labor, 1986-90 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Sheffield: Employment, 1982-86 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sheffield: Technology, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sheffield: Economic policy, 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Sheffield: Industry and government policy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Sheffield: City Council, 1984-85 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Sheffield: Analysis, 1983-85 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Sheffield: Media clips, 1984-86 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Manchester: Economic development and industry strategy, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Manchester: City council, 1984-86 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Manchester: Economic and planning bulletins, 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Manchester: Planning department, 1983-85 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Manchester: Privatization, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Manchester: Analysis, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Lancashire: Enterprises, 1985-90 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Lancashire: Businesses, 1990-91 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Leeds: Business ventures, 1980-87 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
- Leeds: City Council, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Leeds: Urban Development Corp., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Leeds: Economics industry and estates, 1984-87 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Leeds: Economics industry and estates, 1984-87 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Leeds: Analysis of strategy, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Leeds: Economy data, 1980-84 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cardiff: Planning, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Cardiff: Development, 1988-91 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Cardiff: Docklands, 1983-90 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Cardiff: Data, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Cardiff: Urban policy conference, 1991-93 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Cardiff: Chamber of Commerce, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Cardiff: Misc. policy, 1983-86 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Cardiff: City Council, 1983-86 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Cardiff: Enterprise, 1984-91 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- South Glamorgan, 1981-86 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Coventry, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Tyne and Wear UDC, N/A (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Yorkshire: Development Association policy, 1984-86 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Yorkshire: West Yorkshire Enterprise Board and Yorkshire Enterprise Ltd. (WYEB/YE), 1984-87 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Yorkshire: Metro County Council, 1980-85 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Yorkshire: West Yorkshire Metro County Council (WYMCC) analysis, 1980-85 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
- Teeside, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Kent Training and Enterprise Council, 1995-99 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Barnsley - S. Yorkshire, [1985] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Beaver-Leda County, 1986-87 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Birmingham, 1984-87 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Bristol Development Corp., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Huntington City, [1985] (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Edinburgh, 1986-91 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Mersyside Development Corp., 1985-90 (Box 3, Folder 8-10)
- Norwich, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Scotland: Economic development and industry strategy, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Scotland: Local enterprise trusts, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Scotland: Community enterprise, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Scotland: Community business, 1982-91 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
- Scotland: Inverclyde Initiative, 1985-86 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Scotland: Cooperatives development, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Scotland: Development agencies, 1978-88 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Scotland: Enterprise development strategy, 1979-91 (Box 3, Folder 20-23)
- Scotland: Employment and training, 1989-90 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Scotland: Data, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Strathclyde: Economic development and industry strategy, N/A (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Strathclyde: Regional Council, 1982-85 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Strathclyde: Analysis, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Strathclyde: Policy projects, 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Strathclyde: Community businesses, 1985-89 (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
- Strathclyde: Data, 1986-89 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Clydeside, 1985-86 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Clydeside Case Study, 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Glasgow: Community Business News, 1984-91 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Glasgow: Distribution Trades Council, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Glasgow: Analysis, 1982-88 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Glasgow: Opportunities, 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Glasgow: Chamber of Commerce, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Glasgow: Govan Initiative, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Glasgow: GEAR policy, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Glasgow: Glasgow action policy, 1975-87 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Glasgow: City council economic policy, 1981-87 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Glasgow: Data, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- West Midlands: Enterprise boards, 1986-89 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
- West Midlands: Economic Development Review, 1982-86 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- West Midlands: Studies, 1984-87 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- West Midlands: Technology, 1984-86 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- West Midlands: Industry, 1985-87 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- London: Financial strategy, 1983-86 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- London: Labor issues, 1984-87 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
- London: Early warnings, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- London: Contract compliance, 1984-86 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- London: Labor analysis, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- London: LSPU, 1986-87 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- London: Economic development, 1983-90 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- London: Industrial development, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- London: GLC strategy demise, 1985-87 (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
- London: Restart, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- London: Local employee initiatives, 1982-90 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- London: Data, 1984-87 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- National industrial policy, 1984-88 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- UK government intervention, 1984-89 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Reagan and Thatcher Comparison, 1983-89 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- U.K. national economic policy, 1986-88 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Urban development corporations: US/UK Comparison, 1988-91 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Canada: Regional development, 1984-86 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Canada: Unemployment, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Europe 1992, 1989-91 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Europe, 1983-87 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Europe: Thatcherism, 1984-87 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Europe: Employment, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Europe: Employment conference in Leeds, 1985-86 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Europe: Info tech, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Europe: Planning, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Europe: Employee initiatives, 1985-87 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- US/UK comparative studies, 1990-91 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- US economy, 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- US industrialization, 1988-89 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- US urban growth and decline, 1984-86 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- US high tech, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- US: Misc. reports, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- London Boroughs- economic development: Newham, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- London Boroughs - economic development: Southwark, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- London Boroughs - economic development: Islington, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- London Boroughs - economic development: Wandsworth, 1985-86 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- London Boroughs - economic development: Hammersmith & Fulham, 1985-87 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- London Boroughs - economic development: Capital for Transportation, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- London industrial studies, 1983-91 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- London Docklands: LDDC policy, 1983-91 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- London Docklands: Data, 1983-87 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- London Docklands: London Docklands, 1983-90 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- London Docklands: Media clips, 1988-90 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- London Docklands: Policy commentary, 1984-86 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- London Docklands: Alternate policies, 1983-91 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- UK: Regional policy, 1984-87 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- UK: Final regions, 1983-85 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- UK: GB regional economic development, 1967-86 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- UK: ITeCS, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- UK: Rural development, 1984-86 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- UK: Confederation of British Industries, 1985-86 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- UK: Association of British Chambers, 1983-85 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- UK: Plant closings, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- UK: Financial aid to industries, 1983-85 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- UK: BSC industry, 1986-87 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- UK: Industry-manufacturing, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- UK: Local economic development, 1990-91 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- UK: Socio-economic classification, N/A (Box 7, Folder 20)
- UK: Social Audit Network, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- UK: Environment, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- UK: Abstracts, 1989-91 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- UK: Corporate scoreboard, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- UK: Industrial Development Bonds, 1983-90 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- UK: Conference of Socialist Economists, 1984-85 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- UK - taxation and finance: Community organization funding, [1985] (Box 7, Folder 27)
- UK - taxation and finance: Public/private enterprise, 1984-86 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- UK - taxation and finance: Investing, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- UK - taxation and finance: Local government, 1986-88 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- UK labor: Employment article, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- UK labor: Direct labor organizations, 1980-87 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- UK labor: Unemployment, 1984-88 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- UK labor: Routes into work, 1986-87 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- UK labor: Job creation, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- UK labor: Unemployment-national responses, 1981-87 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- UK labor: Trade unions: misc. local alternate proposal, [1985] (Box 8, Folder 4)
- UK labor: Trade unions: research unit publications, 1984-86 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- UK labor: Worker control, 1984-86 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- UK labor: Co-ops, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- UK community businesses: Zoning, [1992] (Box 8, Folder 8)
- UK community businesses: Research and evaluation, 1982-86 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- UK community businesses: Co-op, 1985-88 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- UK small businesses: Minority, N/A (Box 8, Folder 11)
- UK small businesses: Local enterprise agencies, 1984-86 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Economy, 1985-90 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Cities, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Local/central government relations, 1987-89 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Widdicombe local government, 1987-89 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Urban development corporations and agencies, 1987-91 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Urban movements, 1985-86 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Local authorities, 1987-91 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Public sector, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Urban policy, 1987-90 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Enterprise zones, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Urban renewal, 1983-91 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Monitoring, 1985-86 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Employee statistics, N/A (Box 8, Folder 25)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Local economic development, 1984-88 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- UK politics, government intervention and economic development: Planning, 1973-91 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- UK: Replan (Adult unemployed), 1984-87 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- UK: In communities on business, 1981-88 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- UK: "Business in the city", 1984-87 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- UK: Local initiatives in Great Britain, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- UK: Decentralized planning, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- UK: Inner cities, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- CLES: Reports, 1985-91 (Box 8 + 9, Folder 1)
- CLES: Local economic news, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- CLES: Enterprise Boards, 1985-86 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- CLES: Local work, 1986-90 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
- CLES: Briefings, 1986-87 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- CLES: Utilities, 1979-86 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- CLES: LEPU, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- US magazine: Working Papers for Social Research, later changed to Working Papers, 1973-83 (Box 9, Folder 9-18)